notaryrotary.com 2018-05-31

# Notary Rotary - Notary Supplies and Services for the Professional Notary Public

## INTRODUCTION

Notary Rotary recognizes that your privacy and the protection of your personal information is important to you. This statement discloses how we use the personal information stored in the Notary Rotary Web Site (www.notaryrotary.com) and how we protect it. It does not apply to other online or offline Notary Rotary, Inc. sites, products or services.

Notary Rotary is a service that allows users to create an account profile to be used in the marketing of user services and/or the administration of those services. Users consist of agents - mobile notaries public - and those agencies and other consumers who use their services. By using the Notary Rotary Web Site, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## NOTARY ROTARY'S COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

What Information Is Collected by Notary Rotary

When you register for a Notary Rotary account, you will be asked to provide certain personal information that will be stored in your Notary Rotary "profile." As described below, the amount of information requested may vary depending on the type of user (agent, agency, service consumer), but the Notary Rotary profile contains, at a minimum, the following information: (1) e-mail address, (2) first and last name, (3) street address, (4) state and (5) ZIP code or postal code. It may also contain (6) additional personal characteristics, such as phone numbers, secondary addresses, languages spoken and educational levels, agent rank and rating as well as (7) data specific to services rendered, such as loan package reference numbers, borrower information, lender information, signing dates and times, order status and payment details. (8) Notary Rotary also logs individual sign-ins for the purpose of ensuring the efficiency and security of the Notary Rotary service. 

## NOTARY ROTARY'S USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

For the mobile notary public, items (1) through (6) will be available via the Notary Rotary Web Site for anyone to view unless otherwise designated. This enables the advertising of mobile notary services via the Notary Search functionality within the site. The information available for display is administered by the Notary Rotary user within their profile.

For all other users (service consumers), items (1) through (6) will not be disclosed in a public directory format. It may, however, be available to other Notary Rotary users with whom the selected user has a relationship. For example, certain signing agency information, such as billing addresses or terms, may only be available to mobile notaries who have entered into an agency agreement with said company.

Finally, information pertaining to services rendered will be available to parties directly involved in the delivery of the service. This is to include the mobile notary public (agent), the signing agency or closing company (agency) as well as the ultimate service consumer (e.g. a lender). Consider the following example:

(1) Super-Duper Lending Company sells a loan in Des Moines, IA,  
(2) They contact Quick Closings to handle the loan package,  
(3) Quick Closings searches the Notary Rotary database, identifies the agent they would like to handle the closing, and initiates a Signing,   
(4) The agent views the order request in Notary Rotary, completes the closing, and logs the details in Notary Rotary.

In the above scenario, all three of the principal participants would have visibility to the order and its status within Notary Rotary: Super-Duper Lending Company, Quick Closing and the agent.

Except to the extent that a subscription to the Notary Rotary service provides access to certain user information described herein, Notary Rotary will not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. 

Notary Rotary will not use or share your personal information in a manner that differs from what is described in this Privacy Statement without your prior consent.

Notary Rotary may send you e-mail about periodic service or recommended security updates or surveys related to the Notary Rotary Service. These periodic e-mails are considered essential to the provision of the service you have requested. You cannot unsubscribe from these mailings. You may, however, choose not to participate in the surveys.

## NOTARY ROTARY'S GENERAL DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Notary Rotary occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as the publishing of notary materials or manufacture of journals or stamps. Notary Rotary will only provide these companies with those pieces of your personal information needed to deliver the services, and the companies and their employees are prohibited from using that personal information for any other purpose.

Notary Rotary may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: 

(a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process served on Notary Rotary;   
(b) protect and defend the rights or property of Notary Rotary, or Notary Rotary participating sites or services; or   
(c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Notary Rotary Service, or the public.

## MANAGING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

You can always add, update, or make other changes to the information in your Notary Rotary profile by using the Update Profile functionality on the website.

## CLOSING YOUR NOTARY ROTARY ACCOUNT

To close your Notary Rotary account and delete your user profile, please sign on to your account and click the My Profile link for further instructions.

## SECURITY AND STORAGE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Your Notary Rotary information is stored on secured Notary Rotary servers located in controlled facilities. You must type the correct password to access your Notary Rotary information, and your password is never shared with Notary Rotary participating sites or services. It is your responsibility to ensure the security of your Notary Rotary account password and not to share this information during chats, in postings in newsgroups, or in other public forums. If you choose to reveal or share your password and Notary Rotary account name, Notary Rotary is unable to guarantee the security of your Notary Rotary account. 

When you request to have your Notary Rotary information sent to a Notary Rotary participating site, Notary Rotary uses industry-standard security technologies to encrypt it for secure transmission over the Internet.

Personal information collected by Notary Rotary will be stored and processed in the United States only. 

## USE OF COOKIES

A cookie is a very small text file that a Web site saves to your computer's hard disk to store information that you provide about yourself or to store your preferences. Any use of cookies by Notary Rotary is for the express purpose of managing session information and maintaining data security. We do not allow third-party cookies nor do we use cookies to track your activity.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

Notary Rotary will occasionally update this Privacy Statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the bottom of the Privacy Statement. Notary Rotary will obtain your consent for any updates to this Privacy Statement that expand the sharing or use of your personal information in ways not disclosed in this Privacy Statement.

## CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact us using the link at the bottom of this page. You may also contact Notary Rotary by postal mail at:

Notary Rotary  
PO Box 41400  
Des Moines, IA 50311

Version 1.14  
Last Updated: May 23, 2018
